nodesource.com 2019-06-16

# Privacy Policy

Last updated Jun 12 2019

###  **Your Consent**

NodeSource, Inc. (“NodeSource”, “we”, “our”, “us”) are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy. We are a Corporation established in the United States with a registered office at 6017 #399 Snell Ave, San Jose, CA 95123 and for the purpose of the General Data Protection Regulation (the “GDPR”), we are the data controller.

This Privacy Policy (the **“Policy”** ) sets out the basis on which we will process any information we collect from you, or that you provide to us, in connection with your use of our website at www.nodesource.com (the **“Website”** ), our products and our support, consultancy and training services (collectively **“the Services”** ).

If you are using our Services in connection with your employment, your employer is your data controller for the purposes of the GDPR, and we are the data processor collecting and using your information only to provide the services to your employer. Your employer may have their own privacy notices that will apply to your use of our Services. Your employer will have access to your usage information, such as courses taken and results.

Please read this Policy carefully so that you understand how we process your information and what your rights are in relation to your information. You acknowledge that this Policy is part of the Terms of Use and if you do not agree with this Policy in general or any part of it, you should not access our Website or Services. NodeSource reserves the right to change or amend the Policy at any time.Any changes we will make to this Policy will be posted on this page. Please check back frequently for any updates or changes.

###  **What information do we collect and how do we collect it?**

We collect information from you when you use our Website or Services. This includes:

  *  **Online:** We collect information including name, email address, telephone number, employer name, and job title through one or more web properties, (such as NodeSource Accounts). e.g., when you register on our Website, request a free trial or demo, register for a webinar, contact us, subscribe to our email newsletter, download content (e.g. whitepapers), or register to use our products or services, as it is in our legitimate interests to provide our Services, communicate with you and provide customer support per your request. 

  * **Information From Other Sources:** In order to enhance our ability to provide relevant content and offers to you, we obtain information about you including (e.g. name, email address, phone number) from other sources, such as partner organizations, social media platforms, as well as from other third parties.

  *  **Technical Usage Information:** When you visit our Website or use our Services, we automatically collect the information sent to us by your computer, mobile phone, or other access device. This includes IP address, browser and device information, application usage data, information collected through cookies, pixel tags, and other technologies. We use this information as it is in our legitimate interests to facilitate our operation of our Website [and our Services] and for other purposes described below: 

  * to calculate usage levels of our Website and Services;

  * help diagnose problems with its servers;

  * administer the Website and our Services;

  * monitoring the regions from which you navigate to our Website or Services;

  * personalize your experience of our Website and Services; and

  * improve our Website and Services. 

### **How do we protect and secure your information?**

NodeSource goes to great lengths to keep your personal information private and safe. We implement a variety of security measures to maintain the safety of your personal information when you place an order or enter, submit, or access your personal information.

###  **Do we use cookies?**

Yes. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer's hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the sites or service providers systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information.

We use cookies, pixel tags, web beacons, and similar files or technologies to understand and save your preferences for future visits and compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future.

###  **Do we disclose any information to outside parties?**

We do NOT sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information. This does not include trusted third parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential.

We may also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others rights, property, or safety. Occasionally we may be required by law enforcement or judicial authorities to provide personally identifiable information to the appropriate governmental authorities. We will disclose personally identifiable information upon receipt of a court order, subpoena, or to cooperate with a law enforcement investigation. We fully cooperate with law enforcement agencies in identifying those who use our services for illegal activities. We reserve the right to report to law enforcement agencies any activities that we in good faith believe to be unlawful.

While we will use every reasonable means to ensure the security of the information you transmit to us, we cannot guarantee that third parties will not intercept such information. We will, however, prosecute any unauthorized or fraudulent transactions to the fullest extent permitted by law.

###  **How long do we retain your information?**

We will retain your information as follows:

  * if you create an account with us, we will keep your data for 4 years;

  * if you contact us via email, we will keep your data for 4 years;

  * your technical usage information for 4 years;

  * your location data for 4 years; and

  * data on your use of our Services for 4 years. 

After you have terminated your use of your account or our Services, we will store your information in an aggregated and anonymised format.

[If you use our service as an employee of a corporate customer, then your employer will decide who long data is retained.]

###  **Your Rights**

Where you sign up for our Services as an individual, you have certain rights including to find out what information we hold about you and review, update, and correct the personal information you provide us by logging into your account. If you are an employee of one of our corporate customers, please contact your employer to exercise your rights.

You have the right to ask us to access the personal information we hold about you and be provided with certain information about how we use your information and who we share it with. You also have the right to ask us to correct your personal data where it is inaccurate or incomplete and we will endeavour to do so without undue delay.

Where you have provided your personal information to us for your contract with us, you have the right to ask us for a copy of this information in a structured, machine readable format and to ask us to share (port) this data to another data controller.

In certain circumstances, you have the right to ask us to delete the personal information we hold about you:

  * where you believe that it is no longer necessary for us to hold your personal information;

  * where we are processing your personal information on the basis of legitimate interests and you object to such processing and we cannot demonstrate an overriding legitimate ground for the processing; 

  * where you have provided your personal information to us with your consent and you wish to withdraw your consent and there is no other ground under which we can process your personal data;

  * where you believe the personal information we hold about you is being unlawfully processed by us.

  * In certain circumstances, you have the right to ask us to restrict (stop any active) processing of your personal information:

  * where you believe the personal information we hold about you is inaccurate and while we verify accuracy;

  * where we want to erase your personal information as the processing is unlawful but you want us to continue to store it;

  * where we no longer need your personal information for the purposes of our processing but you require us to retain the data for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims;

OR 

  * where you have objected to us processing your personal information based on our legitimate interests and we are considering your objection.

In addition, you can object to our processing of your personal information based on our legitimate interests and we will no longer process your personal data unless we can demonstrate an overriding legitimate ground.

At any time you have the right to object to our processing of information about you in order to send you [promotions and special offers][marketing], including where we build profiles for such purposes, and we will stop processing the data for that purpose.

To exercise any of these rights above, please contact [privacy@nodesource.com](mailto:privacy@nodesource.com). In addition, you have the right to complain to the Information Commissioner’s Office or other applicable data protection supervisory authority.

Please note that these rights above are limited, for example, where fulfilling your request would adversely affect other individuals, our trade secrets or intellectual property, where there are overriding public interest reasons, or where we are required by law to retain your personal data.

###  **Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance**

We are in compliance with the requirements of COPPA (Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act), we do not knowingly collect any information from anyone under 13 years of age. Our website, products and services are all directed to people who are at least 13 years old or older. If we learn that we have collected personal information of a child under age 13, we will attempt to delete that personal information as soon as possible and take any other measures required under applicable law.

###  **International Transfers**

Where the GDPR applies and our processors of your information are located outside the EEA, such transfer will either be: (i) to a recipient certified to the US Department of Commerce's EU-US Privacy Shield; or (ii) subject to the European Commission’s model contracts for the transfer of personal data to third countries (i.e., the standard contractual clauses, the “Model Clauses”). For more information about the EU-US Privacy Shield Framework, visit the U.S. Department of Commerce's Privacy Shield website. If you would like to see a copy of the Model Clauses, please contact [privacy@nodesource.com](mailto:privacy@nodesource.com).

###  **Terms and Conditions**

Please also visit our Terms and Conditions section establishing the use, disclaimers, and limitations of liability governing the use of our website at Terms of Service.

###  **Changes to our Privacy Policy**

If we decide to change our Policy, we will post the amended Policy on this page with the revision date. Please check back frequently for any updates or changes.

###  **Contacting Us**

If there are any questions regarding this Policy you may contact us using the information below.

NodeSource, lnc. 6017 #399 Snell Ave San Jose, CA 95123

privacy@NodeSource.com
